GORDON: Previously on Gotham...
You can't commit
a crime in Gotham
without a license from Penguin.
Tell your families Oswald
Cobblepot keeps them safe.
Not the GCPD.
HARVEY: We'd need an
army to take on Penguin.
I am not giving this
city over to Penguin.
I don't care what the
Commissioner says.
- Makes me miss Falcone.
- I'm done with this business.
I'm out.
I've got a place down
south I can go to.
We need an army. He's got one.
HARVEY: If you show your
face to Falcone, he will kill you.
BARBARA: An
opportunity awaits you.
Why do you want this so bad?
I'm sick of not being
taken seriously.
With you and Barbara,
the three of us could give
all those creeps a
run for their money.
You were the one time
I've met a weakened me.
I want you around
as a constant reminder
to never make
that mistake again.
I'm the one you seek.
I am Ra's al Ghul.
BRUCE: I have to be ready
for when Ra's al Ghul returns.
ALFRED: You need
to find your true north
and let that guide you.
(HORSE SNORTS)
It is here.
At last.
(SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(GASPING)
I was no more.
Now, you live.
How can this be?
The power is in the water.
It has given you life.
And a destiny.
You must find your heir.
As I found you.
Find him.
Be free.
Alfred? You read?
Loud and clear, Master Bruce.
Looks like the rumors
around town are true.
Penguin's bringing
in a big shipment.
Whatever it is,
must be valuable.
He's got four armed
men loading it onto a truck.
I'm gonna go down
for a closer look.
How did I know you
were going to say that?
I'm wearing bulletproof
armor, remember?
Yes. Lucius Fox's
armor was bulletproof.
My mask is not.
Don't get shot in
the face? Got it.
Do I detect a note of
sarcasm, Master Bruce?
BRUCE: Hold on.
I just picked up a thief
heading toward the truck.
Thieves stealing from thieves is
a victimless crime, Master Bruce.
Just walk away now.
They're walking into a trap.
Master Bruce, I'm all for
you protecting the innocent,
but I won't have you
risking your life over a thief.
Now, walk away.
Master Bruce?
Master Bruce!
(GUN COCKING)
STEVEDORE: The hell
are you supposed to be?
You must be real stupid
trying to steal from Penguin.
Bad idea.
(GRUNTING)
STEVEDORE 1: Hold it!
(MEN GROANING)
STEVEDORE 2:
Let's get outta here!
Come on.
In the truck.
(ENGINE STARTS AND
TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIGHS) Damn it!
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Can I help you?
James Gordon. I'm here
to see Carmine Falcone.
He's not expecting me.
Come with me, please.
Carmine.
Jim.
You're a long way from home.
Came down to see you, Carmine.
Heard you retired down here.
Sorry for not calling ahead.
No, you're not.
It's quite the spread
you have here.
I think we're past the
point of small talk, Jim.
Just tell me why you're here.
Morning, Daddy.
FALCONE: How was Artemis?
Feisty as usual. But I
whipped him into shape.
Who's this?
James Gordon.
Jim. Meet my
only daughter, Sofia.
What're you doing here, James?
FALCONE: Go ahead, Jim.
I have no secrets
from my children.
Penguin has taken over the city.
GCPD has turned
its back on Gotham.
There are families
that are still loyal to you.
I need your help to
knock him off his perch.
Sure this isn't about you, Jim?
Your loss of power in Gotham?
This is bigger than me.
You have fight, kid.
I've always admired that in you.
But I can't do
what you're asking.
Why?
Because I'm dying.
Doctors don't know why.
Maybe old age. Karma.
They seem to think the air
is better down here for me.
Give me more time.
I'm not one to
argue with doctors.
Or time.
So, you see. I can't
go back with you.
I'll go back.
Hush.
You're not ready for Gotham.
There was a time in my life
when I would have
done anything for the city.
Those days are gone.
I'm sorry, Jim.
You're on your own.
You sure you know
what you're doing?
(WINCES)
You're mad because I
didn't listen to you, Alfred.
You're damn bloody
right I am. Yeah.
You're right. I let
my guard down.
It won't happen again.
All right. There we go.
Might leave a
little bit of a scar.
Thanks, Alfred.
All right.
(STUTTERING) Now... Where
do you think you're going?
To the docks.
I'm sure there's a
manifest on the freighter.
Whatever is in that
crate must be important
if the thief was willing
to steal from the Penguin.
I want to know what it is.
Right, so being shot
wasn't enough, was it?
You gotta let this
slide, Master B.
There's more to this,
Alfred. I can feel it.
This is my chance to
investigate a real crime.
Stop it before it becomes
something bigger.
Fine.
But just don't go charging around in
broad daylight with that bloody mask on.
It'll be like having a socking great
bulls-eye on your back, all right?
So how do you suggest
I get onto the ship?
There are other kinds
of masks you can wear,
Master Bruce.
(SHUDDERING)
(GRUNTS)
(GUN COCKING)
As you can see, the scatter
pattern is tighter than most.
You won't find a superior
weapon anywhere in Gotham.
- I'll take two dozen.
- Excellent.
You can pay out front.
MAN: Right this way, sir.
Thank you, everyone, for coming.
Tabitha planning
on coming to work?
I am paying her
half the profits.
Don't you mean a third?
That depends.
Where's my crate?
I ran into some trouble.
- Did Penguin's men see you?
- No.
I wore a mask like you said.
- I know you're pissed...
- I'm not mad.
I misjudged you.
I was wrong to cut you
in on my new business.
You're clearly not ready.
You're serious?
I can get the damn thing.
I'll do it myself.
But if you do want
to redeem yourself,
you can do the floors.
Mop's in the closet.
(SCOFFS)
You can mop your
own damn floors.
PENGUIN: Another excellent
night of business, Victor.
Except for the part where
a couple of thieves tried
to rob your shipment.
What?
Relax, boss.
My men stopped them before they
could get their hands on anything.
You see what I'm
dealing with, Ed?
That shipment is full of black
market items I'm auctioning off
tonight to Gotham's elite.
I stand to make a killing.
I cannot do that
without the items.
Where are they?
At the warehouse.
Take me.
I want to be sure
it's all accounted for.
Once I do, bring everything
back here for safekeeping.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(ICE CRACKING)
No! No!
No!
(GASPS)
This cannot be happening.
I don't know. Kind
of opens up the room.
Whoever did this,
I want them found.
I want them dead.
And I want Ed back here, today!
(DOOR OPENS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Where are you, Ed?
(WOMAN GASPS)
Oh! He's up. He's up.
Where am I? How did I get here?
WOMAN: I brought you here.
You're in my home. What do you think?
(NYGMA GASPING)
I'm sorry, but who are you?
You don't remember?
Hilltop Elementary?
Mrs. Macher's class?
I was third row,
closest to the window?
Eddie. It's me. Myrtle Jenkins.
(LAUGHS)
Um, I followed your rise
to becoming the Riddler.
I've read every article.
All the police reports.
I guess you could say
I'm your number-one fan.
Okay.
Um, I should get going.
Whoop! That's gonna be tough.
(GASPS)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Why am I tied up?
MYRTLE: You're not.
Your muscles have atrophied
from being on ice. Okay?
But don't worry, these warming
lamps should help thaw you out.
- Ice?
- Yeah.
Last thing I remember was
being frozen by the river.
How long was I on ice?
Five months.
(GASPS)
I know.
Since then,
Penguin opened a club
called the Iceberg Lounge.
You were its centerpiece.
NYGMA: That little freak.
He put me on display
like some caged animal.
Yes.
And I will nurse you back to health
so you can reclaim your throne
as Gotham's greatest villain.
Ha! Ooh! Caveat.
With me as your
sidekick, of course.
Doesn't that sound
wonderful, my love?
(EXHALES)
You lost, kid?
My uncle Al works on your ship.
My aunt hasn't heard from him
in a few days, and she's worried.
There're a few men below deck.
But I'm pretty damn sure none of
their old ladies are looking for 'em.
Listen, I told my
aunt I'd find him.
Can I just take a quick look? I'll
be in and out in a few minutes,
I promise.
Sure. Go ahead.
Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Bet you think you're real
smart giving us the slip.
I don't know what
you're talking about...
Save it. Somebody tried to
steal from this ship last night.
Did this to my face.
Tell me who you're working for.
I assure you, I'm just
here looking for my uncle.
I took a wrong turn.
Assure?
Here's a little advice.
If you're gonna play
the part of a street kid,
learn how to talk like one.
Hey, Andy.
Get over here.
What'd I tell you about
bothering me at work?
Sorry, fellas.
You're right, though.
The boy's acting does
need some work, doesn't it?
(GRUNTING)
You see, improvisation, Master
Bruce, is a very important weapon
in any actor's toolkit.
Shall we go?
There's a knife being
sold at your auction tonight.
I was thinking you
might be kind enough
to sell it to me ahead of time.
And why is this knife
so important to you?
It's not.
I have a client
who's interested.
Gave me a ton of cash.
So, I was hoping to get it for a
lower price and make a profit.
That start with the attempted
five-finger discount last night?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Of course you don't.
I'll triple the opening price.
It'll probably go
for less at auction.
(CHUCKLES) My dear,
wherever you disappeared
to these last few months
has not made you a better liar.
It's clear that this
isn't about profit,
but about your
mysterious benefactor.
He is your client,
(STUTTERS) is he not?
Reveal his identity to me
and you have a deal.
Wow. He's really
got his hooks into you.
See you tonight, I guess.
Don't forget to bring
your checkbook.
Always a pleasure, Oswald.
BRUCE: The knife was
used to embalm King Balahsi.
According to this, he ruled ancient
Mesopotamia for the first century.
What thief in Gotham
would want a knife like that?
That's a good question.
According to the manifest,
the shipment was full of jewels
and expensive art. Yet,
our thief went for the item
with the least intrinsic value.
Well, that tells me
she was a gun for hire.
But who hired her?
I think I just found the answer.
Alfred, look.
This drawing depicts a
man being healed by water.
And look at his eyes.
His face.
Who does that remind you of?
That's impossible.
I mean, this drawing
is 2,000 years old.
I know.
That's him.
That's Ra's al Ghul.
He wants the knife.
I struck out with Falcone.
HARVEY: That right?
Try not to sound
too happy about it.
Look, if you brought
back Falcone,
that would mean gang
wars and blood in the streets.
And I don't like it when
the streets are bloody, Jim.
Yeah, see how you
like it with Penguin.
See you tomorrow, Harvey.
SOFIA: Mind if I join you?
What are you doing here?
I figured you didn't know anyone in
town. Thought I'd keep you company.
Or maybe I just didn't
want to drink alone.
To my dad.
I am sorry about your father.
We may have had our
differences over the years,
but I always respected him.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
When I was a little girl,
if I wanted to spend
time with my father,
he'd have me schedule
an appointment.
Save the respect. I
know who my father is.
Took him getting sick for us to
finally have a real relationship.
How long have you
lived down here?
Since I was 13.
My father thought sending me away
from Gotham would keep me safe.
I mean, there are
worse places to grow up.
People are happy here.
You see the sun every day.
And I wasn't alone. I had Mario.
We took care of each other.
I know there's
nothing I can say.
I am sorry for what
happened to him.
You're right. There is
nothing you can say.
He was infected with the virus.
You did what you had to.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
There's no sign of Nygma
anywhere in Gotham.
Word on the street is
it's an inside job.
Find whoever is
in charge of hiring.
Kill them.
I want everyone
here interrogated.
There's a traitor amongst us.
(GASPS)
MYRTLE: Those needles should
help stimulate your muscles.
You'll have feeling
back in no time.
(LAUGHING)
Just call me the Riddlette!
I know. What do you think?
I think that rehashing someone
else's idea isn't very original.
(SIGHS)
It's an homage.
And I thought you'd like it.
It's very nice.
(GIGGLES)
This is so much fun.
If only I were the criminal
mastermind you are,
we would've been
together sooner.
I'm sorry, I don't
really follow that.
Well, it took me months
to plan your escape.
I had to learn Penguin's
schedule. When he came and went.
Devise an exit strategy.
I'm sure it would've taken you
two seconds to think something up.
It is slightly impressive you
were able to outwit Oswald.
MYRTLE: Hmm.
Though, as you say, my plan
would've taken much less time.
Oh, wait. That is a great idea.
You should tell me what
your plan would've been.
Because a window into your master
villainy would mean so much to me.
Um...
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Oh.
Here I am bombarding
you with silly questions.
After everything you've been
through, you must be exhausted.
Yes.
- Yes, I must be exhausted.
- (BELL DINGS)
Ooh. Soup's ready.
Do you like tomato? I put
little question marks in it, too.
Last one.
One. Two. Three.
Anything, my love?
No! Acupuncture
is therapeutic snake oil.
I've been focused on
repairing the wrong muscle.
What?
Your brain.
It fires synapses that carry
neurons to the rest of your body.
If we can stimulate it,
perhaps your other
muscles will follow.
- Logical.
- Yeah.
- What do you suggest?
- Well,
in anticipation of our partnership,
I have been working on a few
riddles.
Yes!
Riddles! That's
exactly what I need.
That's gonna make me
feel like myself again.
Fire away.
Okay. Here goes.
What's black and
white and red all over?
Easy. Zebra with
a gaping hole. Next.
No, it's actually a newspaper.
That's ridiculous. There's
nothing red on a newspaper. Next.
- Well, it makes sense, if...
- Next!
Um...
I have a face and two
hands, but no arms or legs.
What am I?
Deformed baby. Come on.
Surely, you can
do better than this.
The answer is a clock. Hands...
I think something is
wrong with your brain, Ed.
There is
nothing wrong with my brain.
The problem is your riddles.
Bring me a riddle
that is worthy of my name.
GORDON: Next time, I'll
know to pack a swim suit.
You actually own one?
Yeah. I got a nice two-piece.
He comes with a sense of humor.
You ever think about
walking away from it all?
Gotham?
Sometimes.
But I can't.
Why not?
It's in my blood.
My father spent his entire
life fighting for the city.
Never took the easy way out.
Neither can I.
What?
Give 'em to me.
I don't really think
they're your size.
Come on.
- That too?
- Mmm-hmm.
- What are you doing?
- Come on.
You can't be serious.
Just a little water, Jim.
GORDON: I can't remember
the last time I just stood still.
All right, Master Bruce.
Let's go over the plan again.
It's simple.
I show up at the
auction and buy the knife.
Should be easy
enough. I am a billionaire.
And a very public one at that.
Turning up at the Penguin's
black market auction
is certainly gonna raise
a few eyebrows. Innit?
You're the one that said that
bidding on it was the smarter play.
That I did. But I didn't mean
going in as yourself. Did I?
What do you think the idea was
going down to the docks
pretending to be someone else?
I was trying to
teach you a lesson.
Now, if you're going to
continue down this vigilante path,
Master Bruce,
you've got to learn
how to assume
other roles.
Play the role
that you were born to play.
That of a privileged someone.
Pedantic teenager
with deeper pockets
than anybody else in this city.
You mean behave
like a spoiled brat.
It goes against everything
that your beautiful parents
tried to ingrain in you.
But, yes,
sir.
Bruce Wayne.
Billionaire brat.
Two hundred and fifty thousand.
Two hundred and fifty thousand
dollars going once, twice...
Sold. To Mr. Bruce Wayne.
(LAUGHS) That's what
I'm talking about! I love art.
I love it! Yeah!
I'm gonna put it in my bathroom.
(CROWD GASPS)
Steady on, Master Bruce, let's
not overplay our hand, shall we?
I must admit, this is fun.
And try to exercise a
modicum of financial restraint.
I know technically you are
the richest man in the room,
but let's not try and buy
absolutely everything, shall we?
True. But if I only bid on the
knife everyone's been trying to steal
from Penguin, it might
draw his suspicion.
If I go on a spending spree,
recklessly throwing my money around,
he won't think twice.
Nice. When did
you think of that?
Improvisation, Alfred.
It's a weapon in
any actor's toolkit.
All right, sir. Here we go.
Oswald! My friend.
Bruce Wayne? What
a lovely surprise.
You certainly are getting out
quite a lot these days. Aren't you?
The way I see it, everyone
else in this town is having fun.
- Why shouldn't I?
- I agree.
You and your insanely
large bank account
are more than welcome here.
- Ha!
- (PENGUIN CHUCKLES)
Barbara Kean.
I thought she died.
Unfortunately, nobody
stays dead in this town.
Excuse me.
You do realize, don't
you, Master Bruce,
that if you actually win,
Ra's al Ghul will
come after the knife.
Let him.
The next item up for
auction is an embalming knife.
From the tomb of King
Balahsi of Sumeria.
Opening bid will
begin at $50,000.
A hundred thousand dollars.
What does she want with it?
I have no idea.
Stay focused.
One hundred thousand
dollars to Ms. Kean.
- Do I hear...
- One hundred thousand and one dollar.
AUCTIONEER: Actually,
Mr. Wayne, the bidding amounts are...
- Two hundred thousand dollars.
- Fine.
We have $200,000. Do I hear...
Two hundred
thousand and one dollar.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Mr. Wayne.
How about you let someone
else have some fun?
Oh! Sure. No problem.
I'm sorry about that.
- Three hundred thousand.
- AUCTIONEER: Very well,
three hundred thou...
Three hundred thousand dollars
and one cent.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Five hundred thousand.
Now back off. You little brat.
Wow, Ms. Kean.
That's a lot of money.
For someone like you.
Two million dollars!
(ALL GASPING)
BARBARA: Two...
Sold to Mr. Bruce Wayne.
(LAUGHS)
Congratulations, Bruce.
Thank you.
(LAUGHING) I do love
seeing that woman lose.
A little piece of
friendly advice.
Barbara Kean does
not give up easily.
She'll be coming for that knife.
I would just, uh, keep a
close eye on it if I were you.
There's a new wrinkle, isn't it?
What's green and red
and goes round and round?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Someone's obsessed
with the color red.
The answer obviously
isn't newspaper.
You're stalling.
(CHUCKLES) No.
You don't know the answer.
Of course I do.
No, you don't. Ed!
- (GASPS)
- Mmm-hmm.
Your brilliant mind is as
damaged as the rest of your body.
Actually,
my body is feeling fine.
Frog in a blender!
(WIND BLOWING)
BRUCE: Selina?
Why are you sitting
in the dark by yourself?
I was expecting someone else.
Like who?
Doesn't matter.
What are you doing here?
I heard about Penguin's auction.
So, Barbara sent
you for the knife.
Figured, what? Because we're
friends I'd just hand it over?
Something like that.
Why is it so important to her?
How should I know?
She was supposed
to get it for some client.
Said he was a
pretty dangerous guy.
And that if you were smart,
you'd hand it over and
save yourself the trouble.
So, you're here to protect me.
Is that it?
The knife can't possibly
mean that much to you, Bruce.
I don't know.
Like you said, I spent $2
million on it. I think I'll keep it.
- Why are you acting like this?
- Me?
What about you? Are you really
Barbara Kean's errand girl now?
I'm her partner.
But if I don't give
her this knife back,
she won't ever
see me as an equal.
I'm asking you to do me a solid.
I'm sorry, Selina.
You should go.
Morning, Harv.
HARVEY: Jim, hey.
This is Detective Harper. She just
transferred over from the three-five.
- Jim Gordon.
- Nice to meet you, Detective.
Heard a lot of good things.
From who?
It's good to have you
in the fold, Harper.
Thanks.
ALVAREZ: Gordon.
You got a visitor.
HARVEY: Hot damn.
Fox in the hen house.
No offense, Harper.
HARPER: None taken.
But you got the
wrong idiom, Captain.
- No, I don't.
- Be right back.
Sofia?
What are you doing here?
I came to help you.
Yeah? How is that?
Penguin. Oh, I know you
didn't directly ask me, but...
I find men tend to have trouble
seeing the simple solution
even when it's
presented to them.
You shouldn't have
come back here.
Oh, Jim.
(EXHALES) I don't need
your permission. Or my father's.
I'm a Falcone.
This city is my birthright.
My father might
not think I'm ready.
But I am.
Is that so?
What do you think I've been doing
down south, the past 10 years?
You knew you were coming back
from the moment I
left your father's house.
Everything that's
happened was what?
You sizing me up?
No. Not everything.
But I had to get to know you
if we're gonna work together.
We're not.
Don't be sore, Jim. You
came looking for a gangster.
That's exactly what you found.
We can do great things
together, you and I.
I'll be in touch.
You?
You're the one
who stole from me?
MYRTLE: Some good it did.
The ice broke his brain.
What are you talking about?
What's green and red
and goes round and round?
Frog in a blender.
Exactly. Ed couldn't
even get that.
It does seem unlike Ed
to keep this rube alive.
Sound the word.
I want him found.
And her?
A lot of people have been
trying to steal from me lately.
An example needs to be made.
Have fun, Victor.
- Love your dress.
- Thank you.
I made it. (SOBS)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Excellent technique, Barbara.
I'm impressed.
I had a good teacher.
I wish you'd have called ahead.
Does that mean you
don't have the knife?
No. Bruce Wayne has it.
Bruce?
Really?
How interesting.
- You're not angry?
- No. Not at all.
You see, Barbara,
when I bathed you
in the Lazarus Pit,
I did it in the knowledge
that you would become
a competent ally of mine.
And so far,
you've done an admirable job.
I'm glad you feel that way.
And I wouldn't worry
about that knife.
Didn't seem all
that special to me.
Oh, but you couldn't
be more wrong.
You see,
that knife
is the key
to everything.
Well, not everything.
English - SDH